Tams-Witmark Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music (Box 1-829)
  - Kremser, Edward, 1838-1914
    - Der Botschafter*, Manuscript full score; [Fragile]. (Box 260)
    - Der Schlosserkönig. Wien: Gustav Lewy, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph); (2 copies). (Box 261)
  - Krenn, L. and Lindau, K.
    - Ein Armes Mädel, Manuscript parts (Box 820)
  - Kreutzer, Conradin, 1780-1849
    - [Nachtlager von Granada]
      - Das Nachtlager, Manuscript parts (Box 262)
  - La Touche, Digby
    - Themidor. Munich: Drei Masken, 1911, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 263)
    - Themidor. Munich: Drei Masken, 1911, Manuscript and printed parts (lithograph); So ein Luderleben (Box 264-265)
  - Lacome, P(aul), 1838-1920
    - [Jeanne, Jeannette, et Jeanneton]
      - The Marquis, Printed parts (Box 266)
  - Lalan, Hans
    - Im Edelgrund und Tiefen Wald oder Die Müllerin und ihr Kind, Manuscript full score (Box 821)
    - Im Edelgrund und Tiefen Wald oder Die Müllerin und ihr Kind, Manuscript parts (Box 821)
  - Laube, Heinrich
    - Prinz Friedrich, Printed libretto (Box 822)
  - Lauchaume, Aimé
    - Prima donna, Printed parts (Box 267-268)
  - Lecocq, Charles, 1832-1918
    - [Coeur et la main]
      - Heart and hand, Manuscript full score (Box 269)
      - Heart and hand, Manuscript parts (Box 270-271)
    - La Fille de Madame Angot, Manuscript parts; Orchestrated by E.H. Moore. (Box 272)
    - Giroflé-Girofla, Manuscript parts; Arranged by Charles Kurth. (Box 273)
    - Giroflé-Girofla, Manuscript parts (Box 274)
    - Giroflé-Girofla, Manuscript parts (Box 275)
    - Giroflé-Girofla, Manuscript full score (Box 276)
    - Giroflé-Girofla, Manuscript parts; Acts II-III only; Orchestrated by Charles Kurth, Jr., 1883. (Box 276)
    - [Jolie persane]
      - The Pretty Persian, Manuscript parts (Box 277)
    - Le Petit duc/The Little duke, Manuscript parts (Box 278)
    - La Petite mariee. Paris: Brandus & Cie, n.d., Printed parts (Box 279)
  - Lehár, Franz, 1870-1948
    - Eva. Leipzig: Ludwig Doblinger, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. D. 4803. (Box 807)
    - [Lustige Witwe]
      - Merry widow*, Manuscript part (contrabass) only; (2 copies). (Box 280)
      - Merry widow, Manuscript part (bass vocal part) only (Box 807)
    - Der Rastelbinder, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 280)
    - Wo die Lerche singt... Leipzig: W. Karczag, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. W. K. 1161. (Box 807)
  - Leoncavallo, Ruggero, 1858-1919
    - Pagliacci. Milan: Eduardo Sozogno, 1903, Printed full score; Plate no. 1038. (Box 281)
    - Pagliacci, Manuscript full score (condensed) (Box 281)
  - Linné, Hans S.
    - A Lovely liar, Manuscript full score (Box 282)
  - Lortzing, Albert, 1801-1851
    - Die Beiden Schützen, Manuscript full score; [Fragile]. (Box 283)
    - Der Wildschütz, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 284-285)
    - Der Wildschütz, Manuscript full score; Act III only (Box 284-285)
    - Der Wildschütz, Manuscript full score; 2 vols.; Acts I-II only (Box 286)
    - [Zar und Zimmerman]
      - Czaar und Zimmermann, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 287)
  - Löw, W. Constantin, 1828-1905
    - In feindes Land, Manuscript full score (Box 288)
    - Wein, Weib, Gesang, Printed full score (lithograph); [Fragile]. (Box 288)
  - Luders, Gustav, 1865-1913
    - The Grand mogul, Manuscript full score (Box 289)
    - The Gypsy, Manuscript full score (Box 290)
  - Manas, Josef
    - Die Royalisten. Braunschweig: Henry Litoff's, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 291)
  - Mannstaedt, W[ilhelm], 1837-1904
    - Das Milchmädchen von Schöneberg. Berlin: U. Kühling, n.d., Manuscript piano-vocal score (Box 808)
    - Das Milchmädchen von Schöneberg. Berlin: U. Kühling, n.d., Printed libretti; (2 copies). (Box 808)
  - Marchetti, Filippo, 1831-1902
    - Roy Blas. Milan: F. Lucca, n.d., Manuscript parts and reduced score; printed string parts; Plate no. 18847b. (Box 292-295)
    - Roy Blas, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 296)
  - Marschner, Heinrich August, 1795-1861
    - Hans Heiling*, Manuscript Full score; [Fragile]. (Box 297)
  - Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945
    - Cavalleria rusticana*, Manuscript full score (Box 298)
    - Cavalleria rusticana, Manuscript full score; [Fragile]. (Box 299)
  - Massé, Victor, 1822-1884
    - Les Noces de Jeanette. Paris: Magasin de Musique du Conservatoire, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. Mme C. 643. (Box 300)
    - Les Noces de Jeanette/Jeanette's wedding, Printed parts; Plate no. Mme C. 614. (Box 301)
    - Paul and Virginia, Manuscript full score (condensed); Arrangement only. (Box 302)
  - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912
    - Le Cid, Printed full score; Plate no. G.H. 1598. (Box 303)
    - Manon, Printed parts (Box 304)
    - Manon, Manuscript parts (Box 305-310)
    - La Navarraise, Manuscript parts (Box 311)
    - La Navarraise, Manuscript full score; extra instrumentation (one folder) (Box 312)
  - Méhul, Étienne Nicolas, 1763-1817
    - Joseph. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 6496. (Box 312)
  - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847
    - Athalia. Felix Mendelssohn's Werke: kritisch durchgesehene Ausgabe. Ser. 15, No. 115. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. M.B. 115. (Box 313)
    - Elias. Felix Mendelssohn's Werke: kritisch durchgesehene Ausgabe. Ser. 13, No. 86. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. M.B. 86.; [Fragile]. (Box 313)
    - Elias. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed parts; Plate nos. Orch. B. 815/817; 4649. (Box 313-314)
    - Die Erste Walpurgisnacht. Leipzig: Fr. Kistner, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 1403. (Box 314)
    - Heimkehr aus der Fremde. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 8354. (Box 315)
    - Heimkehr aus der Fremde. Felix Mendelssohn's Werke: kritisch durchgesehen Ausgabe. Ser. 15. No. 122. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. M.B. 122. (Box 316)
    - [Lobgesang]
      - Hymn of Praise. London: Novello, Ewer & Co., n.d., Printed full score (Box 316)
    - Loreley. Felix Mendelssohn's Werke: kritisch durchgesehene Ausgabe. Ser. 15. No. 123. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. M.B. 123. (Box 316)
    - A Midsummer night, Manuscript full score (Box 317)
    - Midsummer night's dream, Manuscript full score; Vocal selections arranged by T. Yourres Chubb. (Box 318)
    - Sommernachtstraum. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 6059/5056. (Box 318)
    - Midsummer night's dream. [Leipzig]: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed parts; Plate no. Orch. B. 909/910. (Box 318)
  - Mercadante, (Giuseppe) Saverio (Raffaele), 1795-1870
    - Il Giuramento, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 319-320)
    - Il Giuramento, Manuscript full score; Act III Spartitino; Act I - Introduzione; stage band score (Box 320)
    - Il Giuramento, Manuscript full score; 2 vols.; Acts I-II only (Box 321)
  - Messager, André, 1853-1929
    - Les P'tites michu, Manuscript parts (Box 322)
  - Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864
    - L' Africana, Printed full score; 2 vols.; Acts III-V; Plate no. L.B. 1 (15-17). (Box 323)
    - L' Etoile du nord, Printed military band score; Plate no. B. et Cie 9404. (Box 324)
    - Les Huguenots*/Gli Ugonotti. Milan: Ricordi, n.d., Manuscript and printed parts; Plate nos. 53424 (1st ed.), 35618, M. S. 1235 and 2135. (Box 324-328)
    - Pardon de Ploërmel/Il pellegrinaggio di Ploermel. Paris: G. Brandus et S. Dufour, n.d., Printed full score; Plate nos. plate no. B. et D. (Box 328)
    - [Prophète]
      - Il Profeta, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 329-331)
    - [Robert le diable]
      - Roberto il diavolo, Manuscript full score; 4 vols.; Acts I-II, IV-V only (Box OV-332-333)
      - Robert der Teufel, Manuscript full score; Act I only (Box 334)
      - Robert der Teufel, Manuscript full score; Acts II, IV-V only (Box 335-336)
      - Robert der Teufel, Printed full score (incomplete); [Fragile]. (Box 337)
  - Michaelis, Gustav, 1828-1887
    - Bummelfritze, Manuscript parts; [Fragile]. (Box 808)
    - Bummelfritze, Manuscript libretto (Box 808)
    - Ein Gemachter Mann. Berlin: T. G. Breuß, 1883, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 338)
    - Kyritz Pyritz, Manuscript full score (Box 808)
    - Kyritz Pyritz, Manuscript part (Box 808)
    - Kyritz Pyritz. Leipzig: Philipp Reclam Jun., n.d., Printed libretti; (5 copies).; All copies are annotated. (Box 808)
    - Kyritz Pyritz, Manuscript part books (Box 808)
    - Die Lachtaube, Manuscript piano-vocal score (Box 808)
    - Die Lachtaube, Manuscript parts (Box 808)
    - Die Lachtaube, Manuscript libretto (material inserted) (Box 808)
    - Der Mann im Monde, Manuscript full score (Box 809)
    - Der Mann im Monde, Manuscript parts (Box 809)
    - Der Mann im Monde. Leipzig: Philipp Reclam Jun., n.d., Printed libretti (Box 809)
    - Der Verkaufte Schlaf*, Manuscript full score (Box 338)
  - Mielke, Georg
    - Winzerliesel. Leipzig: Gustav Richter, n.d., Printed libretto (Box 809)
  - Millöcker, Carl, 1842-1899
    - [Apajune der Wassermann]
      - Apajune, Printed full score (lithograph); Last few pages are manuscript.; [Fragile]. (Box 338)
    - Der Arme Jonathan/Poor Jonathan, Printed piano-vocal score; R.A. (Box 339)
    - Jonathan. n.p.: Saalfield, 1890, Song of the impresario; Woulds't then still dream? only (Box 339)
    - Poor Jonathan, Manuscript parts (Box 339-340)
    - Der Arme Jonathan*, Manuscript full score (Box 341)
    - Poor Jonathan/Der Arme Jonathan*, Printed parts (lithograph) (Box 342)
    - Poor Jonathan, Manuscript vocal parts; Acts I-II only (Box 343)
    - Der Bettelstudent, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 344)
    - [Dubarry]
      - Gräfin Dubarry, Manuscript full score (Box 345)
      - Gräfin Dubarry, Printed full score (lithograph); [Fragile]. (Box 346)
      - Gräfin Dubarry, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 347)
    - Eine vom Ballet*, Manuscript full score (Box 348)
    - [Feldprediger]
      - The Black hussar*, Printed full score (lithograph); 2 vols.; Acts I-II (Box 349)
    - Gasparone*, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 350)
    - Die Jungfrau von Belleville. Wien: Gustav Lewy, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph); [Fragile]. (Box 351)
    - Nordlicht. Wien: Gustav Lewy (or Jos. Eberle & Co.), n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 352)
    - Der Probekuss. Hamburg: Aug. Cranz, 1895, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 352)
    - Der Probekuss, Manuscript full score (Box 353)
    - Der Probekuss. Hamburg: Aug. Cranz, 1895, Printed full score (lithograph); incomplete (Box 354)
    - The Seven Suabians, Printed full score (lithograph); 2 vols. (Box 355)
    - Die Sieben Schwaben/Seven Suabians, Manuscript full score (Box 356)
    - Das Sonntagskind. Hamburg: Aug. Cranz, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 357)
    - Das Verwunschene Schloss, Manuscript full score; [Fragile]. (Box 358)
    - Vice Admiral, Manuscript full score; [Fragile]. (Box 358)
    - Vice Admiral, Manuscript full score; 2 vols.; [Fragile]. (Box 359)
  - Mohr, [?]
    - Luftschoefser, Manuscript piano-vocal score (Box 809)
    - Luftschoefser, Manuscript parts (Box 809)
  - Monckton, Lionel, 1861-1924
    - A Country girl*, Manuscript full score (Box 360)
  - Morse, Woolson, 1858-1897
    - [Dr. Syntax]
      - Dr. Sintax*, Manuscript full score (Box 361)
    - [Lost, stolen or strayed]
      - Lost, strayed or stolen, Manuscript full score (incomplete?); Typwritten list of musical numbers. (Box 361)
    - Panjan drum, Manuscript full score: Act I only (Box 362)
    - A Pull that's all together, Manuscript full score and parts for Trio: A Pull that's all together; [Fragile]. (Box 362)
    - Wang, Manuscript full score (Box OV-766-767)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
    - Bastien und Bastienne. Wien: Gustav Lewy, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph); (2 copies). (Box 364)
    - Cosi fan tutte. Stuttgart: G. A. Zumsteeg, n.d., Printed full score; 2 vols.; Plate no. 1363. (Box 364)
    - [Don Giovanni]
      - Der Don Juan oder. Leipzig: Steinerne Gast Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; 2 vols. (Box 365)
      - Don Juan. [Leipzig]: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; 2 vols.; Plate no. Moz. D. G. (Box 366)
      - Don Juan, Manuscript full score (incomplete?) (Box 367)
      - Don Juan. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; [Fragile]. (Box 368)
    - [Finta giardiniera]
      - Die Gärtnerin. Wien: Gustav Lewy, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph); (2 copies). (Box 368)
    - Marriage of Figaro, Manuscript full score (Box 369)
    - Marriage of Figaro, Manuscript piano score; Voi che sapete only (Box 369)
    - Nozze di Figaro. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 6252. (Box 370)
    - Il Re pastore. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 371)
    - Requiem. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 371)
    - Requiem. Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart's Werke: kritisch durchgesehen Ausgabe. Ser. 24, No. 1. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. W.A.M. 626. (Box 371)
    - Requiem, Manuscript parts (Box 371)
    - Requiem. Offenbach a/M: Joh. André, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 5018. (Box 371)
    - Der Schauspiel Direktor, Manuscript full score (Box 372)
    - Der Schauspiel Direktor. Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart's Werke: kritisch durchgesehen Ausgabe. Ser. 5, No. 16. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. W.A.M. 486. (Box 372)
    - Der Schauspiel Direktor, Manuscript full score (Box 372)
    - Thamos, König in Ägypten, Manuscript full score; choral score (Box 372)
    - Il Flauto magico. Bonn: N. Simrock, n.d., Printed full score; printed piano-vocal score (incomplete); Plate no. 1092. (Box 373)
    - Die Zauberfloete. [Leipzig]: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1870, Printed full score; Critical comments in introduction.; Plate no. 10923. (Box 374)
  - Müller, Adolf [Sr.], 1801-1886
    - Der Galante Vicomte, Manuscript full score (Box OV-375)
    - Der Liebeszauber, Manuscript full score (Box 376)
    - [Lumpacivagabundus]
      - Lumpaci*, Manuscript full score (Box 383)
      - Lumpacivagabundus, Printed libretto (Box 809)
  - Müller, Adolf [Jr.], 1839-1901
    - Der Hofnaar*, Printed full score (lithograph); 2 vols. (Box 377)
    - Der Hofnaar, Printed full score (lithograph); 2 vols. (Box 378)
    - Der Kleine Prinz. Wien: Gustav Lewy, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 379)
    - Der Millionenonkel. Wien: Gustav Lewy, n.d., Manuscript and printed full score; (2 copies). (Box 380)
  - Müller, Wenzel, 1767-1835
    - Die Schwestern von Prag, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 381)
    - Die Drei Schwestern von Prag, Manuscript parts; [Fragile]. (Box 382)
  - Neidlinger, William Harold, 1863-1924
    - Ulysses*, Manuscript full score; parts (Box 384)
  - Nelson, Rudolph
    - Fräulein Schwindelmeier. München: Drei Masken-Verlag, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. D.M.V. 6. (Box 810)
    - Fräulein Schwindelmeier, Manuscript parts (Box 810)
    - Miss Dudelsack. Berlin: Harmonie, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. 288. (Box 810)
    - Miss Dudelsack, Printed piano-vocal score (incomplete)(2 folders) (Box 810-811)
    - Miss Dudelsack, Printed parts (from manuscript); (2 folders) (Box 811-812)
    - Miss Dudelsack, Printed vocal part books (from manuscript) (Box 812)
    - Miss Dudelsack, Printed libretti (Box 812)
  - Nesmüller, Josef Ferdinand, 1818-1895
    - Die Wilde Toni. Leipzig: Otto Teich, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. O.T. 1697. (Box 812)
    - Die Zillerthaler, Manuscript full score (Box 385)
    - Die Zillerthaler, Manuscript parts (Box 812)
  - Nessler, Viktor E(rnst), 1841-1890
    - Der Trompeter von Säkkingen. Leipzig: J. Schuberth & Co., 1884, Printed full score (lithograph); 3 vols.; Plate no. 6049. (Box 385-387)
    - Der Trompeter von Säkkingen. Leipzig: J. Schuberth & Co., 1884, Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. 6048. (Box 813)
    - Der Trompeter von Säkkingen, Printed piano-vocal score (incomplete); Plate no. 6055. (Box 813)
    - Der Trompeter von Säkkingen, Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. 6444 (missing pages); Plate no. 6072. (Box 813)
    - Der Trompeter von Säkkingen, Manuscript parts (Box 813)
    - Der Trompeter von Säkkingen, Manuscript vocal parts (Box 813)
  - Neuendorff, Adolf, 1843-1897
    - Don Quixote, Manuscript full score (Box 388)
    - [Der Rattenfänger von Hameln]
      - The Rat-Charmer of Hamelin, Printed piano-vocal score; Manuscript synopsis laid in.; (2 copies). (Box 814)
      - The Rat-Charmer of Hamelin, Manuscript parts (Box 814)
      - The Rat-Charmer of Hamelin, Typed libretto (Box 814)
      - The Rat-Charmer of Hamelin, Manuscript synopsis; miscellaneous (Box 814)
  - Newcomb, James
    - Der Traum des Lebens, Typed libretto (Box 814)
  - Nicolai, Otto, 1810-1849
    - Die Lustigen Weiber von Windsor, Manuscript full score (Box 389)
    - Die Lustigen Weiber von Windsor. Leipzig: C.F. Peters, n.d., Manuscript full score; Plate no. 6593. (Box 390)
    - Merry wives of Windsor*, Manuscript full score; recitatives only (Box 391)
    - Merry wives of Windsor*, Manuscript full score; recitatives only (Box 392)
  - Northrup, Theodore H.
    - Ship ahoy*, Manuscript full score; parts (Box 393)
    - Ship ahoy, Manuscript full score (Box 394)
  - Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
    - [Barbe-bleue]
      - Blaubart, Manuscript full score; parts (Box 395)
      - Bluebeard, Manuscript and printed parts; Plate no. 10469. (Box 396-397)
    - Die Schöne Helena, Manuscript full score (Box 398)
    - La Belle Helene, Manuscript full score (Box 399)
    - Belle Lurette, Manuscript parts (Box 400-401)
    - [Braconniers]
      - Poachers, Manuscript full score (Box 402)
      - Poachers, Manuscript parts (Box 403)
    - The Brigands, Manuscript parts (Box 404)
    - Brigands, Manuscript parts (Box 405)
    - Les Brigands, Manuscript parts; Orchestrated by George A. Itzel. (Box 406)
    - Les Brigands, Manuscript parts (Box 407)
    - [Chanson de Fortunio]
      - Das Sonntagskind (A Child of fortune)*, Printed full score (lithograph); 3 vols. (Box 408)
      - Fortunio's Lied. Berlin: Bote und Bock, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 409)
      - Fortunio's Lied, Manuscript full score (Box 411)
    - [Contes d'Hoffmann]
      - Countess d'Hoffmann*, Manuscript full score (condensed); scenes and recitatives only (Box 412)
    - Daphnis & Chloe, Manuscript full score (Box 413)
    - [Fille du tambour major]
      - Drum major's daughter. Paris: Choudens, n.d., Manuscript parts (Box 413)
      - The Drum major*, Manuscript parts (Box 414-415)
    - Geneviève de Brabant, Manuscript parts (Box 416-417)
    - [Grande duchesse de Gérolstein]
      - The Grand duchess, Manuscript full score; reduced orchestration (Box 418)
      - Die Grossherzogin von Gerolstein, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 419)
    - [Jacqueline]
      - Dorothea, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 420)
    - [Jeanne qui pleure et Jean qui rit]
      - Die Hanni weint, der Hansi lacht, Manuscript parts (Box 421)
      - Hanni weint, der Hansi lacht. Berlin: Bote und Bock, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 422)
    - [Lischen et Fritzchen]
      - Fritzchen und Lieschen, Manuscipt full score (Box 422)
      - Fritzchen und Lieschen. Berlin: Lange, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 422)
    - Madame Favart*, Manuscript parts; [Fragile]. (Box 423)
    - Madame Favart, Manuscript parts (Box 424-425)
    - Madame Favart, Manuscript parts (Box 426)
    - [Mari à la porte]
      - A Husband locked out, Manuscript parts (Box 427)
      - Der Ehemann von der Thuer/Mari à la porte, Manuscript full score (Box 427)
    - [Mariage aux lanternes]
      - Marriage by lanterns*, Manuscript full score (incomplete) (Box 428)
      - Love by lantern, Manuscript parts (Box 428)
    - Monsieur et Madame Denis*, Manuscript full score (Box 429)
    - Herr Schlapp und Frau (Mr. et Madame Denis), Manuscript full score (Box 429)
    - Herr und Madame Denis, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 430)
    - Herr und Madame Denis, Manuscript parts (Box 431-432)
    - Herr und Madame Denis, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 433)
    - [Mr. Chofleuri restera chez lui le...]
      - Mr. Chofleuri, Manuscript parts; Arranged by Reiff. (Box 420)
    - [Nuit blanche]
      - Forty winks, Manuscript full score (Box 410)
    - Eine Hochzeitsnacht, Manuscript full score (Box 434)
    - Orphée aux enfers, Manuscript full score (incomplete); [Fragile]. (Box 435)
    - Orphée*, Manuscript full score (Box 436)
    - Orpheus, Manuscript full score (Box 437)
    - Orpheus, Manuscript full score (Box 437)
    - Paimpol & Perinette, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 438)
    - [Pépito]
      - Das Mädchen von Elizondo, Manuscript full score (Box 438)
    - Perichole, Manuscript full score (Box 438)
    - [Permission de dix heures]
      - Urlaub nach dem Zapfenstreich. Berlin: Bote und Bock, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 439)
    - [Princesse de Trébizonde]
      - Die Prinzessin von Trapesunt, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 439-440)
      - Princesse of Trebizonde, Manuscript parts (Box 441-443)
      - Princess of Trebizonde, Manuscript parts (Box 444)
    - [66]
      - Non 66 oder die beiden, Manuscript full score (Box 445)
    - Die Savoyarden, Manuscript full score (Box 445)
    - [Vie parisienne]
      - Pariser Leben, Printed full score (lithograph); 4 vols. (Box 446-447)
    - [Violoneux]
      - Die Zaubergeige, Manuscript full score (Box 448)
    - Martin der Geiger, Manuscript parts (Box 448)
    - Martin der Geiger, Manuscript full score (Box 449)
    - Martin der Geiger, Manuscript full score (Box 449)
  - Pacini, Giovanni, 1796-1867
    - [Pompeja (L'ultimo giorno di)]
      - Last day of Pompeii*, Manuscript full score; Act II only (Box 772)
    - Saffo, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 450-451)
  - Paer, Ferdinando, 1771-1839
    - L' Agnese, Manuscript full score; 4 vols. (Box 452-453)
  - Pascal, Florian [Joseph Benjamin Williams], 1847-1923
    - The Jewel maiden*, Manuscript full score (Box 455)
  - Pedrotti, Carlo, 1817-1893
    - Fiorina, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 456-457)
  - Perfall, Karl Freiherr von, 1824-1907
    - Junker Heinz. Wien: Gustav Lewy, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 457)
  - Planquette, Robert, 1848-1903
    - Nell Gwynne, Manuscript parts (Box 458)
    - Nell Gwynne*, Manuscript full score (Box 459)
    - Nell Gwynne, Manuscript parts (Box 459)
    - Paul Jones, Manuscript parts (Box 460)
  - Platzbecker, Heinr[ich]
    - Fundevogel und Lenchen. Dresden: E. Neumann & Co., n.d., Printed piano-vocal score (Box 815)
  - Pleininger, Karl, 1841-?
    - Die Alten Deutschen, Manuscript full score (Box 461)
  - Ponchielli, Amilcare, 1834-1886
    - Gioconda. Milan: Ricordi, 1915, Printed full score; Plate no. 115330. (Box 462)
    - La Gioconda*, Manuscript stage band score (Box 462)
  - Raimann, Rudolf, 1861-1922
    - D'Artagnan und die drei Musketiere. n.p.: Stadler Stubenvoll, 1881, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 463)
  - Reinhardt, Heinrich, 1865-1922
    - Das Süsse Mädel. Vienna: Doblinger, n.d., Printed parts (lithograph) (Box 464-465)
  - Reinthaler, Karl Martin, 1822-1896
    - Bismarck-Hymne. Berlin: Simrock, 1876, Printed full score; Plate no. 7841. (Box 466)
  - Reiterer, Ernst
    - Frühlingsluft. Wien: Ludwig Doplinger, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. D 2879.2882. (Box 815)
    - Frühlingsluft, Manuscript parts (2 folders) (Box 815)
    - Frühlingsluft, Printed and manuscript vocal parts; [Fragile]. (Box 816)
  - Reyer, (Louis-Etienne-) Ernest, 1823-1909